JONATHAN ARMSTRONG DATA ANALYST

Summary

I am a data analyst specializing in public education. I have experience wrangling, cleaning, analyzing, and modeling data to suite needs district and campus needs while applying in-depth domain knowledge based on hands on experience in the classroom.

Employment

Southwestern Adventist University

Data Analyst

Keene, Texas Feb. 2022 to May 2022

Analyzed student and staff survey data to provide up to date results and aggregations to departments

(Temporary position until May 2022)

Bay City ISD

Lead Teacher Elem

Bay City, Texas July 2017 to July 2021

- -Utilized Organization Health Improvement data to develop campus improvement plan
- -Analyzed behavioral data on Multi-Tiered System of Support team to create and monitor campus behavior management
- -Monitored and visualized student academic data regularly
- -Supported team in implementation of classroom technology
- -Lead and organized team meetings to establish grade-level long and short term goals.

Projects

Python and Google Slides: Peripheral Recommendations to Improve District STAAR Meets Score

Gathered and cleaned TEA snapshot district data for state of Texas in 2018. Used exploratory data analysis to gather insight on actionable features and the relationship of those features to STAAR data. Used machine learning to predict STAAR scores for 2020 data as well as offer suggestions to two districts on how to raise the number of students meeting the STAAR in their area.

Python and Tableau: Analysis and Prediction of Math Placement Cleburne ISD

Cleaned district data on student demographics and math performance for the 2020-21 academic year. Used exploratory analysis with Tableau to create a dashboard for the District Assistant Superintendent in charge of data and campus performance which compared aggregate student performance to differences between campuses. Utilized machine learning to predict whether 5th grade students would approach, meet, or master the math STAAR.

Volunteering

Cleburne ISD · Data Analyst Intern Cleburne Texas

Dec. 2021 to Current

Worked with assistant superintendent to perform analysis and draw insights on pain points for the district

Contact

- **■** ionathan.alan.armstrong@gmail.com
- ♦ https://github.com/jonarms/Portfolio
- **\$179336841**

in www.linkedin.com/in/jonathanarmstrong-data

Education

Springboard Data Science Career Track

Aug. 2021 to Feb. 2021

Portfolio Projects linked 6-month intensive course in data science, machine learning, Python and SQL.

Southwestern Adventist 2009 to University 2013

BS Communication 2013

Skills

LANGUAGES: PYTHON (PANDAS, NUMPY, SEABORN, SCIKIT), SQL

STATISTICAL ANALYSIS: DESCRIPTIVE AND INFERENTIAL STATISTICS, REGRESSION MODELING, HYPOTHESIS TESTING